All right, let's talk about how to
navigate Visual Studio Code now that
you've got it installed. Um, so when
we're working throughout this course,
you're going to want to be working in a
folder. So the way you do that is you
just click this open folder button and
then you navigate on your computer to a
folder that you want to use. For me, I'm
going to put it on my desktop. So I'm
going to come to my desktop and I'm
going to click new folder and I'm going
to give this folder a name. Um, I'm
going to name it first website. You
probably don't want to have any spaces
in the name. So, I'm going to name it
first website. And then I'm going to
click on first website. And I'm going to
click open.
Okay. And then it's going to say, do you
trust this computer? Um, and also if
you're on a Mac, it's going to ask you
if you want to allow Visual Studio Code
access to this folder that you just
created. I would like to give it access
and I created this folder. So I do trust
the author of this folder. So I'm going
to say yes, I trust the authors.
Hopefully you trust yourself. All right.
So
in what we have here is the main Visual
Studio Code view. So this here in on the
main big pane is where you will see all
of the code that you're going to write.
This lefth hand panel right here is your
file explorer and it shows you all of
the files and folders that are in your
project. Right now it's completely empty
because we don't have anything here. On
the lefth hand panel you can change what
this little pane shows you. So right now
it's showing me the file explorer. Um
later we're going to talk about source
control and version control. And you'll
click on this button to view that. Um,
if you want to talk about debugging,
this is the button you'll click on. And
then this one right here that looks like
three blocks with a block falling off
the top of it, um, is called extensions.
And extensions allows you to extend
Visual Studio Code's capabilities. So
you can make Visual Studio Code your
own.
So for example,
in this course, some helpful extensions
to have would be the live server
extension. So, if you type live server
and it's this top one right here, um,
and then you'll click install. What that
does is it someone else wrote some code
that extends Visual Studio Code and then
it allows you to make updates to your
code and you can see your website update
live just like this video is displaying
right here. So, I'm going to go ahead
and hit install and it's going to say,
do you trust this developer? I have used
live server for several years. I do
trust this developer. So, I'm going to
say trust publisher and install.
And then it takes a minute, but now it's
installed. And once it's installed,
you'll see this little go live button
show up at the bottom right. When you're
in an HTML file, you'll be able to click
that button and it will show you what
your website looks like. We'll talk
about HTML in the next video. Um, I just
want to get you oriented to Visual
Studio Code. Um, the other thing that's
helpful is you can come down here and
click the settings and then you can
click command pallet. When you hover
over command pallet, it'll tell you what
the keyboard shortcut is to pull up
command pallet. In this case, the
keyboard shortcut on a Mac is shift
command P. On a Windows, it's control
shiftp. So, I'm going to hit command
shiftp. And it pops up this little bar
up here that allows me to change some
things about how Visual Studio Code
works. The goal of this video is for you
to make Visual Studio Code your own. Um,
so, um, one of the things that I like is
I like to change the color theme. So, I
type the word theme here and then I'm
going to say preferences, color theme,
and I'm going to click that. And then
there are a bunch of different themes
that you can pick. So, I could make it
red. Um, that'll change how my code
appears. I could change the preference
theme to and I just as I mouse down
through these, you can see what the
theme is going to look like. I don't
love light theme, but if you do, go for
it. Um, any of these light themes I try
to avoid. Um, I'm going to stick with
dark plus, but I hope that you find a
theme that's helpful for you. So, I'm
going to select well, guess that's the
theme we're going with today because I
clicked the wrong one. um I will change
it back to dark plus for the rest of the
series. Um so that's how you get live
server
and then
um if there are other extensions that
you want you can search for them through
this extensions marketplace. Um so a
popular one is if you're programming in
Python it's helpful to have the language
support. Um, so you can see a whole
bunch of popular um, extensions here and
I've used several of these, but for now
we'll just stick with having you get
live server. Um, and that should about
wrap up this video. Thanks for watching.